<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Amjad Ali]]></title>
  <link href="http://amjd.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://amjd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T20:35:02+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://amjd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Amjad Ali]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[User verification by missed calls]]></title>
    <link href="http://amjd.github.io/blog/2014/01/12/user-verification-by-missed-calls/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-12T09:23:26+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://amjd.github.io/blog/2014/01/12/user-verification-by-missed-calls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever worked on a web or mobile app, odds are you must have come across a scenario where you had to verify users&#8217; phone numbers by a text message or call. It could be for phone number verification or maybe for two-factor verification. Regardless of the use case, it would typically require you to use a service like <a href="http://www.twilio.com">Twilio</a> or <a href="http://www.nexmo.com">Nexmo</a>. This may not look like much as they offer simple, RESTful APIs, but it still takes some work getting it to work with your app.</p>

<p><strong>Enter mOTP.</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://motp.in">mOTP.in</a> is a free service which takes a fresh persective at this phone verification space. Instead of text messages or voice calls, mOTP uses the concept of missed calls to verify the user. I don&rsquo;t know how much missed calls have caught on in other countries but they have various uses in India, which is where mOTP hails from.</p>

<p>Anyway, what mOTP does is, it calls the user from a number like +NNNNNNNN where the numbers following the + sign represent the verification code. The call is disconnected within a second or less, just long enough to leave the evidence of a missed call. The advantage with this approach is it&rsquo;s free for the company as well as for the users.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen how reliable it is. For what it&rsquo;s worth, it worked alright when I tried it . Give it a shot and let me know what you think in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy New Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://amjd.github.io/blog/2014/01/01/happy-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T21:21:11+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://amjd.github.io/blog/2014/01/01/happy-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just wishing everyone a Happy New Year. There are exciting things planned for this site in the near future. Cheers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://amjd.github.io/blog/2013/12/25/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-25T16:19:25+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://amjd.github.io/blog/2013/12/25/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have always been a lazy blogger. I have lost track of just how many times I&rsquo;ve begun a blog with the hope of finally being an active blogger, only to abandon it again after a few days of enthusiasm. This time I&rsquo;m determined to get past that early stage and start contributing regularly.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s hoping this blog won&rsquo;t suffer the same fate as the ones before it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
